Blacks in the Railroad Industry on Microfilm 5989 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Blacks in the Railroad Industry on Microfilm
1946-1954
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Scholarly Resources Inc.
5989 mf
0.11 cubic feet
1 microfilm reel
Records, microfilm.
Materials documenting the struggle of black railroad employees.
5745668
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, September 26, 2012
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 10, 2016
Scope and Contents
This is a compilation of a variety of materials documenting the struggle of black railroad employees against ouster from the industry by the collusive actions of the companies and the unions. The papers have been divided into six sections: 1) Correspondence 2) Unions and Union-related organizations 3) Writings 4) Legal documents 5) Memoranda, and 6) Printed Material.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Arrangement
Series Unions and Union-Related Organizations
Series Printed Material
Railroads -- Employees -- History; African Americans -- Employment -- History; Scholarly Resources Inc.
5745668
- Correspondence, 1949-1950; 1 (Reel 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Also includes undated correspondence
- Series Unions and Union-Related Organizations
  - Negro Railway Labor Executives Committee, 1948-1949; 2 (Reel 1)
  - Railway Employees Association against Discrimination, 1953-1954; 3 (Reel 1)
  - United Transport Service Employees-CIO, 1949; 4 (Reel 1)
  - Membership Rosters, 1949; 5 (Reel 1)
- Writings: Untitled Typescript, 6 (Reel 1)
- Legal Documents, 7 (Reel 1)
- Memoranda: Hearings on U.S. House of Representatives Special Subcommittee on Education and Labor, 1949; 8 (Reel 1)
- Series Printed Material
  - National Negro Labor Council, 1954; 9 (Reel 1)
  - Negro Railway Labor News, 1948-1950; 10 (Reel 1)
  - Fact Sheets, 1946-1953; 11 (Reel 1)
    1946-1947, 1953. Also includes undated correspondence
  - Press Releases and Newspaper Clippings, 1948-1953; 12 (Reel 1)